Ardian Bahtiarsyah

Software Engineer

As an experienced software engineer with a strong desire to build and create, I have successfully founded and launched some products from the ground up, which have provided me with not only valuable technical expertise but also a unique perspective on business operations.

I am also currently serving as an engineering manager to expand my people management skills within the software development industry.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Speech - Work In Progress

https://speeech.app Learn English words with Al.

Tech Stack:

- NodeJS
- Flutter
- Azure Speech-to-Text API
- PostgreSQL

Apisentris

https://apisentris.com

https://www.producthunt.com/products/apisent ris#apisentris-2

Convert databases to APIs without coding. Tech Stack:

- · Ruby on Rails
- Redis
- PostgreSQL
- Docker

Maker Message - Failed

https://www.producthunt.com/products/maker-message

Tech Stack:

- · Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL

EXPERTISES

Ruby / Rails9 years of exp.NodeJS7 years of exp.Typescript3 years of exp.ReactJS3 years of exp.Golang1 year of exp.Docker5 years of exp.AWS7 years of exp.

Eng. Management 2 years of exp.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Solo Founder & Engineer

Dec 2017 - Current (~5 years)

Apisentris

This is currently on auto-pilot and organic growth.

Apisentris offers a simple solution for accessing databases through a RESTful API. This currently supports MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and also Google BigQuery.

Launched twice on ProductHunt and got its first customer from there. https://www.producthunt.com/products/apisentris#apisentris-2

Software Engineering Manager (promoted)

Apr 2021 - Current (~2 years)

Quipper - Indonesia (remote)

Managing 2 squads, the Recommendation squad, and the Campus squad.

The primary purpose of the Recommendation squad is to reduce the time for the student to find relevant content for their learning.

While Campus squad owns everything you see on campus.quipper.com. The main purpose is to connect campuses and students in Indonesia.

Lead Software Engineer (promoted)

Oct 2020 - Mar 2021 (6 months)

Quipper - Indonesia (remote)

Leading the Quipper Video team to deliver product features:

- Let's Learn Again
- Content Search on Web
- Topic Recommendation (collaborative project with Quipper Japan's Data Team

Software Engineer

Jan 2020 - Sep 2020 (9 months)

Quipper - Indonesia (remote)

- Maintain and improve on common core features (features that are leveraged by services. e.g: user account management, video chapters, quiz, etc)
- Maintain and improve API integrity (e.g. define modularization architecture strategy, API structure, etc)
- Ensure interoperability between services

EDUCATION

Computer Science Dian Nuswantoro University, Indonesia

2008 - 2012

Bachelor's Degree - GPA 3.64

Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2017 - Dec 2019 (2 years 10 months)

Forstok - Indonesia

One of Forstok's founding team. Joined Forstok when there was no user and saw how it grows over time. What I did:

- Built core features
- RnD for marketplace API integration
- Integrate Magento API
- Integrate Magento2 API
- Integrate Shopify API
- Integrate Matahari Mall API
- Integrate Elevenia API
- Integrate Zalora API
- Integrate Tokopedia API
- Built Forstok Open API
- Built export to channel's metrics gem to be used across services
- Built export item service (microservice)

Software Engineer

Jan 2015 - Feb 2017 (2 years 2 months)

May 2014 - Feb 2017 (2 years 10 months)

Nov 2012 - Apr 2014 (1 years 6 months)

Phybbit - Japan (remote)

Part of Qivtech developer as extended team for Phybbit.

Senior Software Engineer **Qivtech - Indonesia (remote)**

Worked on client's projects

Walden Global Service - Indonesia

Worked on client's projects

Software Engineer